

☑ gianlucazoni@outlook.com ・ 🌴 www.gianlucazoni.com ・ 🖸 GianlucaZoni ・ 🛅 gianluca-zoni

I'm an ambitious designer with a passion for outdoors and anything with a chip inside, I strive to make meaningful content to make the world a tiny bit better.

## Summary.

DevOps Engineer at fintech & blockchain company Dunamu which is known for operating Upbit, the largest cryptocurrency exchange in Korea. Have led growth at infrastructure departments in two fintech companies as lead engineer and founding member. 12+ years of diverse software engineering experience with specialties in software architecture design, infrastructure operation, backend development, and security engineering.

Love to contribute to open sources and tech communities by sharing knowledge and experience. Prefers a command line interface environment as a big fan of Vim, Linux, and macOS. Always trying to customize to find the most optimal environment. Interested in devising a better problemsolving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools.

# Work Experience\_

#### PoliMovies Cinematography & Film Making Association

Milan, Italy

CO-FOUNDER & VICE-PRESIDENT

Jun. 2023 - Present

PoliMovies is the first designers-led student association at Politecnico di Milano,

dedicated to creating a vibrant community of aspiring filmmakers and cinephiles.

Our mission is to promote cinematography culture to students through curated movie screenings and cine forums, hands-on workshops to develop storytelling and film production skills, and collaborative production projects. We provide opportunities for members to explore the art and craft of filmmaking, develop their skills, and showcase their creative talents.

- Coordinated licensing agreement for the screening of movies
- Managing relations with entities and brands collaboration for the organization of events
- Producer and Post Production Supervisor for the projects led by the association

Politecnico di Milano Milan, Italy

STUDENT AMBASSADOR Apr. 2023 - Present

· Counseling students in discovering the field of Digital and Interaction Design and getting to know life at Politecnico di Milano

Softec S.p.A. Milan, Italy

Internship in the Marketing and Design department of the company

Assisted the Design team in transitioning from Sketch to Figma

Politecnico di Milano Milan, Italy

IT CONSULTANT & INNOVATIVE TECHNOLOGIES TUTOR

Mar. 2021 - Dec. 2021

May. 2022 - Jul. 2022

Collaboration with METID department in Politecnico di Milano assisting schools during the COVID-19 pandemic with distance learning, counseling teachers and students in the use of digital and innovative learning platforms

· Performed programming lessons in an elementary school utilizing a tailored educational version of the popular video game Minecraft

#### **Honors & Awards**

Winner, MESAthon Human-Computer Interaction 24h Challenge

Online

### **Education**

UI DESIGNER

Politecnico di Milano Milan, Italy

MASTER OF SCIENCE IN DIGITAL AND INTERACTION DESIGN Sep. 2022 - Now

Politecnico di Milano Milan, Italy

Sep. 2019 - Jul. 2022 BACHELOR'S DEGREE IN COMMUNICATION DESIGN

GIANLUCA ZONI · RÉSUMÉ FEBRUARY 9, 2024